MIROSLAV TUSHEV

225-937-6341 \phi miroslavtushev@gmail.com \phi miroslavtushev.com \phi github.com/miroslavtushev

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science

2022

Louisiana State University, Department of Computer Science **Topic**: Digital Discrimination in the Sharing Economy

Advisor: Anas Mahmoud

M.S. in Computer Science

August 2018

Louisiana State University, Department of Computer Science **Topic**: Using GitHub in Software Engineering Education

Advisor: Anas Mahmoud

B.Sc in Management

May 2014

The Russian Presidential Academy of National Economy and Public Administration

PROFILE

I am a research assistant at Louisiana State University with 3 years of experience in mobile app analytics and software engineering. Skilled in statistical analysis, including inferential and descriptive statistics, experiments, and machine learning, with the focus on NLP.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analysis: pandas, numpy, sklearn, scipy, spacy, keras, tensorflow, NLTK, gensim, SPSS, Stata

Programming: Python, Java, C#, C, bash, tex, html, CSS

Visualization: matplotlib, seaborn, ggplot, networkx

PUBLICATIONS

- Classifying Mobile Applications Using Word Embeddings
 E. Ebrahimi, M. Tushev, and A. Mahmoud, Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), 2021.
- Analysis of Non-Discrimination Policies in The Sharing Economy
 M. Tushev, F. Ebrahimi, and A. Mahmoud, Intr. Conf. on Soft. Main. Evol (ICSME'21)
 Acceptance rate: 43/179 (24%)
- 3. Mobile App Privacy in Software Engineering Research: A Systematic Mapping Study F. Ebrahimi, M. Tushev, A. Mahmoud, Information and Soft. Tech. (IST), 2020.
- Modeling User Concerns in Sharing Economy: The Case of Food Delivery Apps
 G. Williams, M. Tushev, F. Ebrahimi, and A. Mahmoud, Auto. Soft. Eng. (ASEJ), 2020.
- Digital Discrimination in Sharing Economy: A Requirements Engineering Perspective M. Tushev, F. Ebrahimi, and A. Mahmoud, Inter. Requirements Eng. Conf. (RE'20) Acceptance rate: 20/82 (24%)
- Linguistic Documentation of Software History
 M. Tushev and A. Mahmoud, Inter. Conf. on Program Comprehension (ICPC'20)
 Acceptance rate: 8/14 (57%)
- 7. On Combining IR Methods to Improve Bug Localization S. Khatiwada, M. Tushev, and A. Mahmoud, Inter. Conf. on Prog. Compr. (ICPC'20).
- 8. Using GitHub in Large Software Engineering Classes: An Exploratory Case Study M. Tushev, G. Williams, A. Mahmoud, Computer Science Education (CSE), 2019.

- 9. Linguistic Change in Open Source Software
 - M. Tushev, S. Khatiwada, A. Mahmoud, Intr. Conf. on Soft. Main. Evol (ICSME'19) Acceptance rate: 26/46 (57%)
- An Information Theoretic Approach for IR-Based Software Bug Localization
 Khatiwada, M. Tushev, A. Mahmoud, Information and Software Technology (IST), 2018.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

May 2018 to present

Louisiana State University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering

I conduct research in the area of Software Engineering under the supervision of Dr. Anas Mahmoud. In my research, I analyze large datasets of user feedback (reviews, tweets). My current project involves applying NLP state-of-the-art models, ML, and statistical techniques to extract and classify user concerns in Gig Economy apps (Uber, Lyft, Airbnb, etc.) My previous work included mining software repositories, with emphasis on linguistic change in Open Source Software (OSS) and using OSS in SE education.

Teaching Assistant

August 2018 to May 2020

Louisiana State University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering

· CSC 4330 Software Systems Development (100+ students), CSC 2262 Numerical Methods with MATLAB (60 students), CSC 1351 Computer Science II for Majors with Java (100+ students), CSC 1253 Introduction to Computer Science with C++ (up to a 100 students), Computer Science and Programming for K-12 students (summer camp, 20 students)

Graduate Assistant

August 2015 to May 2018

Louisiana State University, International Services Office

PRESENTATIONS AND TALKS

- 1. Analysis of Non-Discrimination Policies in The Sharing Economy International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution (ICSME), 2021 (virtual).
- 2. Digital Discrimination in Sharing Economy: A Requirements Engineering Perspective Inter. Requirements Engineering Conf. (RE), 2020 (virtual).
- 3. Linguistic Documentation of Software History Inter. Conf. on Program Comprehension (ICPC), 2020 (virtual).
- 4. Linguistic Change in Open Source Software International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution (ICSME), 2019.

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

• Student Volunteer

International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2021)

• Web and Social Media Chair

Crowd-Based Requirements Engineering (CrowdRE 2020, 2021)

• Program Committee

International Working Conference on Requirements Engineering: Foundation for Software Quality (REFSQ 2022)

IEEE International Requirements Engineering Conference. Artifacts Track (RE Artifacts 2021)

International Conference on Software Engineering. Demo Track (ICSE Demo 2020)

Mining Software Repositories 2021 (Shadow PC)

• Reviewer

Empirical Software Engineering, Journal of Software: Evolution and Process